Hello, and welcome back. As such I just mentioned in the previous
大家好 欢迎回来 正如我在上一个视频中所提到的
video we are going to now see a few examples of image and video processing.
现在我们将看到一些图像和视频处理的例子
That's going to help us to understand basically, what is image and video
这将有助于我们理解什么是图像和视频处理
processing. And it's also going to provide a few
并且我们还将展示一些例子
examples of the material that we are going to learn during these nine weeks.
它们有关于我们将在这九周中学习的材料
So let's dive right in. And we're going to start with an example
让我们开始吧 我们以科学图像的例子开始
in scientific images. Scientific images are images that are
科学图像是出于科学目的拍摄的图片
taken with a scientific goal. We want to do some science with those
我们想利用这些图像做一些科学研究
images. And there's probably no better example
或许没有比来自火星的图像更好的例子了
than images from Mars. So we're all very excited when we get the
当我们收到这些 NASA 喷气推进实验室 (JPL)
images. From the NASA JPL expedition to Mars.
探索火星而得的图像时 我们都非常激动
These are really cool images, and we're seeing something that we have
这些图像非常酷 我们看到的是前所未见的景象
never seen before. Now, these images take a lot of space in
现在这些图像在火星车 (Mars Rovers) 的计算机中占了很大一块空间
the computer in the Mars Rovers. They actually take a long time to
事实上 把这些图像传回地球耗费了很长时间
transmit to Earth, because they are very, very large.
因为它们非常非常大
So, NASA and JPL had to implement something inside the Mars Rovers,
所以NASA和JPL必须在火星车上
something which is called image compression, to preserve the information,
实现图像压缩 (image compression) 功能 来保存信息
but try to make that occupy less space, so it is faster to transmit.
同时试图占用更少空间 这样传输得更快
We're going to learn. We're actually going to learn the
我们将要学习的这些 实际上我们要学的正是
algorithm that was implemented in the Mars Rovers.
被应用于火星车的图像压缩算法
I was lucky enough that one of my algorithms was selected to be implemented
我的一种算法被选中并装入了火星车中 这令我感到很荣幸
in a Mars rover. So we're going to learn it, pretty much
所以我们将会非常详细地学习它
in detail. But of course, this is not the only
当然 这并不是唯一的
example, you know, about image compression.
关于图像压缩的例子
If you use the digital camera, most digital cameras today use image
如果你用数码相机的话 如今大部分的数码相机都使用了图像压缩技术
compression. If you're looking images over the web,
当你在网络上浏览图片时
you're basically using image compression. Actually when you are watching this
你其实也是在使用图像压缩 实际上你正在看的这个视频
video, this video is being compressed before it's uploaded to the web so you
在上传网络前供你欣赏也是经过压缩的
can enjoy it. So we're basically doing image and video
所以说 基本上我们一直在用着图像和视频压缩
compression all the time. So that's one example that in your daily
这就是我们日常生活中的一个例子
life, you're already seeing image and video
你已经见过了图像和视频压缩
compression. There's another very important example,
这还有另一个非常重要的例子
and it comes in the movies. If you go to the movies, you're probably
它来自电影中 如果你去看电影
have seen, you might not be aware,
尽管你可能没有意识到
but you have seen image and video compression.
但你已经见过图像和视频压缩了
Let me give you an example. So here we have an image.
让我们来看一个例子 来看这张图片
This is basically one frame of a video. It's a very famous video and what we,
这只是视频的一帧 这是一个非常著名的视频
very famous movie and what we see here these are two consecutive frames so, one
非常著名的电影 这是连续的两帧
coming right after the other and we see here that the actor is basically holding
一帧紧跟着另一帧 我们可以看到在这里演员手中拿着一个玻璃杯
a glass, and right after, he is holding a plate.
紧接着 他手中的又换成了一个盘子
That's very surprising, how he switched a glass to a plane, that's actually a, to a
这令人吃惊 玻璃杯怎么就变成了盘子呢
plate. That's actually a mistake in the movie.
实际上这是电影里的一个纰漏
Here is another example, that we basically see the camera, the cameraman
这有另外一个例子 在图中我们可以看见摄像机 摄影师
is in the picture. Of course, the director didn't want the
导演肯定不想他出现在图中
cameraman in the picture, but it is.
但他确实出现了
And actually, if you saw the movies, when they just came out and you pay
说真的 当电影刚出来的时候
attention to them you actually might have been able to see the cameraman or to see
你仔细去看 非常有可能看见摄影师或者
this mistake. There's actually mistakes in almost all
像这样的错误 几乎所有的电影都有
the movies, and there's a website that shows them.
这样的错误 这有个网站专门收集这些错误
And basically if after that you go and see basically the DVD or different
在那之后 你去看那部电影的DVD或者其他版本
versions of the movie, these repairs, these, these mistakes were repaired.
这些错误都会被修正
And how were they repaired with something called image and video in painting.
我们将会学习图像和视频修复技术是怎样实现这些修复的
And we're going to learn about that. But let's see a few additional examples.
让我们再看一些其他的例子
Because sometimes we need to repair images and videos,
不只是电影 有时候我们还想修复其他的图片和视频
not just for the movies. So for example, here is a picture that
比如说这张图片
looks perfectly fine to us. It's actually a picture of Stalin.
看起来似乎很好 没什么问题 这是一张斯大林的照片
And so here we have Stalin. We see nothing wrong with this picture.
这个人就是斯大林 我们看不出什么问题
The only problem with this picture, this is not an original picture.
但这张图片唯一的问题在于 它不是原图
This was a picture that was inpainted by hand, because actually what really
这是一张经过手工修复的图像
happened was this. This is the real picture.
因为真正的照片是这样的 这才是真的照片
There was another person here, that the picture was retouched,
实际上这里还有一个人 这张图片被修饰过了
and this time, it was done long time ago. It was done by hand.
这是在很久之前由手工完成的修复
It was retouched, so that the person is no longer in the picture.
经过修饰 这个人被从照片中移除了
But, actually today we're going to learn how to do that with basically computer
但是今天我们将学习怎样利用计算机技术来实现修复
techniques. Let's see other examples, because this is
我们来看看其他的例子 这个很有趣
very exciting and also there is a website which we provide those details in, in the
实际上也有一个网站收集这样的有意思的例子
class web page that provides a lot of examples like this.
你可以在课程的网站上找到相关的信息
This is really a fine area. So, here is a frame of a Monty Python
这是一个很有意思的领域 这是蒙提·派森(Monty Python)的一张图片
movie, and as you see its scratches are being made to disappear.
正如你所见 上面的一些划痕被移除了
So, sometimes, you have a very nice image that somebody scratch in it, and you want
所以有时候你的一张很漂亮的图片被人涂鸦了
to make those scratches disappear. What you are seeing now is a simulation
你会想要弄掉它们 你现在看到的是
for real image processing algorithm that is making that scratch slowly disappear.
一个真实的图像处理算法的模拟 它在缓慢的除去这些草稿
And that's going to be part of what we're going to learn.
这将是我们学习内容的一部分
We talked about image compression, that's going to be about the second week of this
我们讨论过的图像压缩将是我们第二周的内容
class. Imaging painting and medium painting is
图像修复和视频修复
going to be towards the second half of the class.
大约是在接近下半学期的时候讲到
Let's see more examples. Here we see a perfectly nice video, this
让我们再多看几个例子 我们看到的这个视频非常完美
is one of my former students, Keller, walking in front of the library at the
这是Keller 他曾是我的学生 从明尼苏达大学的图书馆前走过
University of Minnesota. Doesn't look like anything strange in
视频里看来没什么奇怪的
this video. Only that this was the actual video.
但是这才是真实的视频
Actually, killers wife was walking in front of him, then we applied,
实际上Keller的妻子走在他的前面
image and video processing algorithms, to make her disappear from the video.
然后我们用了一些图像和视频处理的算法 让她从视频中消失
Sometimes we want to get special effects in videos.
有些时候我们想给视频添加一些特效
So this is an example of special effects. We actually start from a black and white
这有个特效的例子 我们从一段黑白电影开始
movie. And here we see a few frames of that
这里我们可以看到黑白电影里的几帧图像
black and white movie. We provide a few hints of some color that
我们给计算机提供了一些提示 标明我们想要添加的颜色
we want to add to the video, and here is the automatic result.
然后就自动生成了这样的结果
Just from hints, actually in this case in just one frame, we get a colorized movie.
只要一帧里的一点提示 我们就能得到彩色的影像
So it's like we're in painting but we're in painting colors into the movie,
这很像在做修复 只不过我们是在影像中修复色彩
just on our special effect. Special effects are all over, and you
这只是使用了我们的特效的结果 特效无所不在
need a lot of image and video processing to do them.
你需要进行大量的图像和视频处理来实现它们
So here is another example. Let me run it first, so it's easier for
这是另一个例子 让我先播放一遍
me to explain the special effect. At first you see kind of blurry.
这样比较好解释它运用的特效 刚开始你看得模模糊糊
This looks like a blurry video. But look what's going to happen.
一眼看上去似乎这个视频很模糊 但是看看发生了什么
We actually have the players, actually are shot.
我们可以看到橄榄球运动员触地得分
The movie was blurry, the background was blurry, but not the players.
这个视频很模糊 背景很模糊 但是运动员很清晰
So let me just try to run it again, so we can see that even better.
我再播放一遍 这样我们看的更清楚
So it's blurry, but the players are not. And we have to do video processing to be
视频很模糊但是运动员除外 我们要运用视频处理
able to get that special effect. Here is yet another example of special
来得到这些特效 这还有个关于特效的例子
effect. I'm going to run it, and you're going to
我播放一遍 你应该就能看出
see basically, immediately what type of special effects we mean here.
这里我们用的特效是什么
We see that the movie's running, but basically the girl, the lady in the movie
我们看到电影正在播放 而这个女孩
is actually being repeated. Okay,
出现了重影
and so it's very easy to observe that here we see repetitions of what's
好 这里的重影非常明显
happening. And that's a very special effect that is
电影工业中大量运用了这个特效
used a lot in the movie industry, especially sometimes for marketing and
尤其是在做广告和市场宣传的时候
advertising. Let me show you yet another example of
让我再给你看一个例子
some really, really interesting special effects.
这个特效真的非常有意思
And this is here. So this is a movie.
就是它了 这部电影
Once again we run the movie. Looks really nice.
再播放一下 看起来很不错
But actually, after we've finished that movie, we might actually want to change
但是实际上但这部电影摄制完成后
the background. So here is the same movie, with a
我们或许会想给它换一个背景 所以这里是同一个影片
different background. Wow.
只是背景有所不同 哇哦
This is a lot of work. As we are going to see.
这需要大量的工作 正如我们将要了解的那样
The basic idea is we're going to have to be able to segment out this person.
一个基本的想法是将这个人分割出来
That's a foreground. That's what we want to keep in the movie.
作为前景 这是我们想要保留在影片中的
We're going to have to find it. We're going to have to extract it from
我们需要把它找出来 并从电影中分离出来
the movie and put it in a new background. That's a really fun thing to do.
然后嵌入到一个新的背景中去 这是一件很有意思的事情
I'm going to run this again. Here is one movie.
我们再来看一遍
Same movie, with a different background. We're going to learn about week five.
同样的电影有着不同的背景 这是我们第五周要学习的内容
What, how to do that,
怎么做到这个
how to extract objects from still images or from movies.
如何从静态图像或是影片中抠出物体来
And actually these type of things show up in commercial products.
实际上像这样的东西已经商业化了
In this case I am showing you a screen shot of what is called aftereffects, is
现在你看到的是Adobe公司出品的Affter Effects软件的一张截图
one of Adobe products. And we actually, in collaboration with
我以及我原来的一个学生与Adobe有合作
Adobe and one of my former students, we develop what I just showed you which are
我们共同研发了你刚才看到的分离物体的技术
techniques to extract objects, so we can basically put them in your
那我们就可以把它们放到我们准备的背景中
backgrounds. And I am going to explain to you exactly,
在一个相对较短的视频里
as many details as I can provide in a relatively short video.
我会尽可能把它详尽地解释给你
I'm going to show you how this is done inside After Effects in Adobe,
我会向你展示Adobe的After Effects是如何完成这些的
some of the underlying technology that appears there.
以及它们所应用到的根本的技术
So these are just some examples of image and video processing.
这就是一些图像和视频处理的例子
We started from image compression. The NASA Rovers have to have image
我们从图像压缩开始 NASA的火星车需要图像压缩
compression. Your digital cameras have to have image
你的数码相机需要图像压缩
The video that you're watching now, has
即使是你正在看的这个视频
to be compressed before it's uploaded to the web.
在上传之前也需要压缩
And we're going to see in the first week of class why,
在第一周 我们将知道为什么
why images occupy so much information. In the second week, we're going to learn
图像占据了如此大的信息 而第二周 我们将学习
how to compress them. We also saw special effects like imaging
如何进行压缩 我们也看到了一些特效
painting, which we are going to see towards the
比如说图像修复 在接近下半学期的时候会讲到
second half of the class. And we saw special effects like
我们将会在第五周左右讲到
segmentation and changing background. And that, we are going to see around week
像图像分割和变换背景的这种特效
five. So a lot of really exciting applications.
这么多令人激动的应用
Some of them, you are very familiar from the movies, from your digital cameras.
有些应用 你从电影和数码相机中得以知悉
Some of them. You actually see everyday, but you're not
有些应用 你每天都见到 却不曾意识到它们的存在
really aware that they are happening. And I'm going to help you to basically
我将会帮助你们透过表象
understand that they are actually happening, behind the scenes.
看到这些特效的运作
And what we are going to do in the next movie, we are going to give a few
下一个视频中我们将会看到更多的例子
additional examples to further motivate you, the importance of image and video
它们将激励你 告诉你图像和视频处理的重要性
processing and also how much fun it is to understand what's happening behind the
并且意识到了解图像视频背后之事的乐趣所在
scenes with images and videos. We are also going to talk in the next
下一个视频中我们还会谈论
video a few examples of medical imaging, an extremely important area in image and
医学影像 (medical imaging) 这是图像和视频处理中非常重要的领域
video processing. So, I am looking forward to seeing you in
我期待在下一个视频中见到你
the next video. Thank you.
谢谢 //果壳教育无边界字幕组 风过成伤 | leafsherry | wugui